Guide to the Iannucci Modern American Literature Manuscript Collection, approximately 1934-1999
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Iannucci Modern American Literature Manuscript Collection
approximately 1934-1999
Iannucci, Brenda J.
0.5 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Manuscript material accompanying the Iannucci Modern American Literature Book Collection.
Biographical Note
Physician and book collector.
Scope and Content Note
Manuscript material accompanying the Iannucci Modern American Literature Book Collection. Includes correspondence, broadsides, manuscripts, and photographs.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Iannucci Modern American Literature Book Collection
Subject Headings
Names:
Bishop, Elizabeth, 1911-1979; Bogan, Louise, 1897-1970; Brinnin, John Malcolm, 1916-; Di Prima, Diane; Glück, Louise, 1943-; Kumin, Maxine, 1925-; Lowell, Robert, 1917-1977; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; McCarthy, Mary, 1912-1989; Sarton, May, 1912-1995
Subjects:
American poetry; American literature--Women authors; Literature--Authors; Women poets
VCL Categories
Literature and Writing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, February 2008.
Custodial History
Collected by Brenda J. Iannucci, then gifted to Barbara Page.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Barbara Page, June 2007.
Container List
- SERIES I: Elizabeth Bishop
  - Card and Penteado drawing sent out with advance copies of Bishop's Complete Poems, (removed from IMALBC volume 2) (Folder 1.1)
  - Vassar College commencement ticket, 1934, (removed from IMALBC volume 1) (Folder 1.2)
  - Pendant given to May Swenson by Bishop (Folder 2.1)
  - Photocopied letter and photograph regarding pendant given to May Swenson by Bishop (Folder 1.3)
  - Mailing announcing the "Consultants' Reunion: Readings by Consultants in Poetry to the Library of Congress," an event at the Library of Congress, 6 Mar 1978 (Folder 2.8)
- SERIES II: Louise Bogan
  - Postcard and letter to Eugene Delafield, 3 June 1964, 30 May 1965; (removed from IMALBC volume 4) (Folder 1.4)
  - Letters from John Wheelock, 1935-1938, 1953 (Folder 1.5)
  - Clippings, (removed from IMALBC volume 5) (Folder 1.6)
  - Clippings, (removed from IMALBC volume 6) (Folder 1.7)
- SERIES III: Brinnin, John Malcom
  - Typescripts of "To the Lighthouse" and "Poem for a Memorial Day," both inscribed to Phillips L. Garman, (removed from IMALBC volume 7) (Folder 1.8)
- SERIES IV: Diane Di Prima
  - "XV Dedications," Unicorn Broadsheet, Series II, no. 7, signed, 1971 (Folder 2.2)
- SERIES V: Louise Gluck
  - "The Mystery," Stern & Faye broadside, no. 15/100, signed, 1999 (Folder 2.3)
- SERIES VI: Kumin, Maxine
  - "On Digging Out Old Lilacs," Pomegranate Press broadside, no. 248/250, 1973 (Folder 2.4)
- SERIES VII: Lowell, Robert
  - Broadsides from "4," printed and signed by Laurence Scott, no. 56/100, Jan 1969; (includes all four broadsides) (Folder 2.5)
- SERIES VIII: McCarthy, Mary
  - Letter to Wesley S. Harley, 17 Aug 1959 (Folder 1.9)
  - Letter to Wesley S. Harley, 24 Apr 1981 (Folder 1.10)
  - Two clippings of Bishop's "Sonnet", (removed from IMALBC volume 3) (Folder 1.11)
- SERIES IX: Marianne Moore
  - Letters to Frederick Adams, Jr., 7 Jan 1949, 30 July 1949; (removed from IMALBC volume 9) (Folder 1.12)
  - Letter to Cherry Lane Theatre, 20 Oct 1954; (removed from IMALBC volume 8) (Folder 1.13)
  - Postcard to Caroline T. Gilchrist, 17 Mar 1965; (removed from IMALBC volume 15) (Folder 1.14)
  - Postcard to Virginia Patterson, 23 May 1954; (removed from IMALBC volume 10) (Folder 1.15)
  - Letters to John B. Rey, 1965-1968 (Folder 1.16)
  - Note to John B. Rey, 24 Mar 1969; (with enclosures) (Folder 1.17)
  - Note to Mary and Bryan Sheedy, June 1968; (removed from IMALBC volume 14) (Folder 1.18)
  - Note to Allen Tanner, 8 Oct 1965; (removed from IMALBC volume 18) (Folder 1.19)
  - Thank-you note to P.K. Thomajan, 14 Aug 1950 (Folder 1.20)
  - Postcard signed "Bill,", ca. 1992; (removed from IMALBC volume 9) (Folder 1.21)
  - "W. S. Landor," Broadside printed by Adams & Lowell House, proof copy signed for Ian Story by Laurence Scott, Aug 1965; (mounted on poster board) (Folder 2.6)
  - "W. S. Landor," Broadside printed by Adams & Lowell House, no 50/135, signed by Moore and Laurence Scott, Mar 1965; (laminated) (Folder 2.7)
  - Signed typescript of "Rigorists" (Folder 1.22)
  - Notes on her poem, "Poetry,", 2 May 1968; (removed from IMALBC volume 14) (Folder 1.23)
  - Signed clipping of "To a Giraffe," from the New York Times, 19 Apr 1963 (Folder 1.24)
  - Notice sent with advance review copies of Nevertheless, 1944; (removed from IMALBC volume 13) (Folder 1.25)
  - Letter from the Hampshire Bookshop to A.B. Churchill, 20 Dec 1951; (removed from IMALBC volume 11) (Folder 1.26)
  - Program from "Poetry in Crystal" exhibition at Steuben Glass, 1963; (removed from IMALBC volume 17) (Folder 1.27)
  - Notice of Moore's reading at the Poetry Center, 17 Nov 1968; (removed from IMALBC volume 14) (Folder 1.28)
  - Clipping re National Medal for Literature, 11 Dec 1968; (removed from IMALBC volume 14) (Folder 1.29)
  - Citation written by John Hall Wheelock for the Academy of American Poets presentation, Oct 1965 (Folder 1.30)
  - Poem for Moore by Eloise C. Parker, 1956; (removed from IMALBC volume 12) (Folder 1.31)
  - Photographs, 1953-1969; (3 prints) (Folder 1.32)
- SERIES X: Howard Nemerov
  - Mailing announcing the "Consultants' Reunion: Readings by Consultants in Poetry to the Library of Congress," an event at the Library of Congress, 6 Mar 1978 (Folder 2.8)
  - Mailing announcing Nemerov's lecture at the Library of Congress entitled "Science and Stories, 1 May 1989 (Folder 2.9)
- SERIES XI: May Sarton
  - "The Phoenix Again," signed broadside printed by Firefly Press for Sarton's 75th birthday, 3 May 1987 (Folder 2.10)
  - "The Ender, The Beginner," signed broadside printed by Firefly Press for Sarton's 80th birthday, 3 May 1992 (Folder 1.33)
- SERIES XII: Edith Sitwell
  - Clippings, signature, etc., (removed from IMALBC volume 16) (Folder 1.34)
- SERIES XIII: Miscellaneous
  - Iannucci annotations and other items removed from the book collection (Folder 1.35)
Volume Index
Index of volumes in the Iannucci Modern American Literature Book Collection (IMALBC) from which manuscript material was pulled.
(01) Bishop, Elizabeth. The Complete Poems. London: Chatto and Windus, [1969].
(02) Bishop, Elizabeth. The Complete Poems. New York: Farrar. Straus & Giroux, 1969 (advance copy for review).
(03) Bishop, Elizabeth. The Complete Poems. New York: Farrar. Straus & Giroux, 1969 (Mary McCarthy's copy).
(04) Bogan, Louise. The Blue Estuaries: Poems, 1923-1968. New York: Farrar. Straus & Giroux, 1968 (copy inscribed to Eugene Delafield).
(05) Bogan, Louise. The Sleeping Fury.. London: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1937 (copy with "Cassandra" inscribed on fly leaf).
(06) Field, Charles K. Cheerio's Book of Days. New York: Garden City Publishing, 1940
(07) Gregory, Horace, ed. New Letters in America.. New York: Norton, 1937.
(08) Kreymborg, Alfred. Others: An Anthology of New Verse. New York: Knopf, 1917.
(09) La Fontaine, Jean de. The Fables of La Fontaine. Translated by Marianne Moore. New York: Viking Press, 1964.
(10) Moore, Marianne. The Absentee. New York: House of Books, 1962 (Signed copy given to Robert Lowell by Marguerite Cohn).
(11) Moore, Marianne. Collected Poems. New York: Macmillan, 1951 (copy with Faber and Faber book jacket).
(12) Moore, Marianne. Collected Poems. New York: Macmillan, 1955 (copy inscribed to Eloise Parker).
(13) Moore, Marianne. Nevertheless. New York: Macmillan, 1944.
(14) Moore, Marianne. O To Be a Dragon. New York: Viking Press, 1959 (copy inscribed to Bryan Sheedy).
(15) Moore, Marianne. Puss in Boots, The Sleeping Beauty, & Cinderella: A Retelling of Three Classic Fairy Tales Based on the French of Charles Perrault. New York: Macmillan, 1963.
(16) Salter, Elizabeth. The Last Years of a Rebel: A Memoir of Edith Sitwell.. Lonodon: The Bodley Head, 1967.
(17) Steuben Glass. Poetry in Crystal.. New York: Steuben Glass, 1963
(18) Watson, Hildegarde Lasell. The Edge of the Woods. Privately printed, 1979.